The way applications are built these
days is fundamentally changing. And in
today's video, we'll be looking at a
novel approach to building things.
Because on this channel, you've seen me
cover many text to application programs.
But never before have we looked at
something that is referred to as an AD,
an agentic development environment. This
is not a command line interface that
builds stuff for you like plot code. And
it's not an IDE like VS Code or
something like cursor that takes VS Code
and adds AI on top. This is an
application that is engineered from the
ground up to build with both humans and
agents working in unison. And in today's
video, I'm exploring this workflow
together with you. And we'll be building
a real world app that I personally
actually need right now. Concretely,
it's something relatively simple, but
the look of it really matters to me
because we'll be building a companion
app for my upcoming book that is coming
in early 2026. The book is all about
introducing newcomers to AI technologies
in chat. And this application we build
today is going to be the digital
companion to the book. So people can
actually get some of the prompts from
the book directly in their browser.
We'll walk through the entire process
together from ideiation to crafting the
prompt to building and refining the
application. And before we get started,
I want to point out that Warp, the
application that we'll be using here
today, is the sponsor of today's video.
But as you know, we pick our sponsors
very carefully. And this is a new
approach doing these things. And I
myself especially enjoy working with
companies that are really trying to
carve out new niches within the AI space
and something that's labeled an agentic
development environment definitely
checks that box. So with that being
said, let's do what I personally enjoy
the most and that's actually build
something. To get started, you will need
to install Warp on your machine.
Luckily, this couldn't be any simpler.
You download the installer whether
you're on a Windows or on a Mac. You run
it and that's really it. All you need to
do now is login with GitHub. This would
be my recommendation as it automatically
links it then and we're ready to work.
So what I'm going to be showing you in
this video is not just the build of the
application within Warp, but also the
ideation stage. And there's multiple
ways to do that. You can do that both
within the LLM of your choice or you can
do it directly within Warp. If you do it
within Warp, the entire workflow is
self-contained. It can plan, it can take
screenshots, you can use various models
and you never have to leave the
application. for me because I have my
worked project set up. In this video,
I'll be showing you the process in chat
GPT, but I will also show the warp
variant on the side. And if you decide
to do this in Warp, I really want to
show you the settings that you should
change in order for you to get the most
out of this. So, as we enter this idea
stage, if you're working within Warp,
you will really want to go to your
profile and then hit settings here and
then go down to AI. You can add
different agent profiles. I'll just edit
the default one that is set up right
here by clicking edit. And the crucial
setting for planning that I want to
bring your attention towards is the
planning model up here where you can
pick which model we want to use. So
maybe I don't want 03. Maybe I want GT5
with high reasoning. And then down here
there's create plans which you might
want to change to always ask. Meaning
that the agent will make plans before
working and asking you about them. This
is very similar to a workflow inside of
any of the CLI tools if you're familiar
with something like the codec cli or
clot code. And then as I mentioned, I'll
be doing this workflow within chat GPT.
But as we go through it, sometimes we'll
also split screen and show you what it
looks like in warp if you want to do
everything in one application. And as
per usual, our build will start with
some ideation. Now to save us some time
and also quite honestly to give me the
space to think through this carefully, I
went through this chat here with chat
chip D5 Pro to flesh out what I really
want from this application. I'll briefly
show you the highlights of this so you
can replicate this for yourself and also
to exactly show you what my workflow in
a situation like this would look like. I
started inside of my worked context
project that includes a comprehensive
overview of my company operations of
everything we do at the AI advantage,
our goals and a quarterly road map with
the descriptions of the various products
we have all in here. And then I always
like to keep a mission, vision, values
file inside of my work context. In
there, I start with a simple prompt
where I use voice dictation to formulate
my first idea. And I let that run
through GPT5 Pro. Now, Pro is optional,
but from all the models, it's my
absolute favorite right now for the
reason that it has the ability to
consistently surprise me with
suggestions that might go beyond the
scope of what I ask for, but ones that I
really like. Basically, I told it about
the companion app for the book. I tell
you about the structure and what I will
provide, and I tell GBT5 Pro that I want
help in fleshing out this application. I
end with some constraints like it not
being overly complex and what the
purpose of this digital application is.
In the end, I just add a little bit of
flavor by telling it to give me some
creative alternatives and I let it go.
As you can see, this is not overly
specific and I don't even include the
content that will be in the application
or what exact format I expect. And this
is how I often work because by not being
too specific in my first prompt, I give
it space to think. This is a
brainstorming prompt, not a do this for
me prompt. So, it came back with a bunch
of fantastic suggestions and some
choices here. So, for example, here in
6, it asks me, hey, these are the free
delivery choices. You could do a static
web app, do it no code for notion, or
you could do it inside of a specific
tool like Obsidian. And then it gave me
all of these creative ideas as I asked
for. These are modular add-ons for me to
consider and so much more HGV5 Pro loves
to do. So, briefly, I just want to show
you what this would look like if we were
to do the process inside of Warp. It's
way more proactive in its planning. So
it creates a project and a GitHub
repository right away and then it gives
me a plan. Now you can see that the plan
includes free features and it proposes a
technical architecture. Whereas here in
chatbt it's just the nature of chatt to
be a bit more conversational. So it
gives me way more options and it's also
the pro model in here that just really
gives me a lot of choices along the way.
Whereas within warp it pretty much tells
me hey this is how I would do it. What
do you think of that? And now I could
accept or reject those edits. But as
mentioned, I'll keep going here with the
chat GPD workflow. But the big advantage
here is I get to choose from all models,
right? So practically on different
projects, I would just try different
approaches. Now let's get back into my
chatb workflow here. And this is where I
start zeroing in on my idea. I follow up
with quite a lengthy prompt with some
examples in here because we're getting
specific at this point in time. And you
can see I start out by saying create a
prompt for V1 of the AI builder app.
Also, there will be no login just to
clarify that. That was something that
came up in here. Then I continued to
describe this image that I found on the
web and I said I attach an image of a
prompt organizer layout that I like. No
need for editing or adding new ones in
this app. Of course, I just found this
off a quick Google search and I like the
simplistic layouts. The aesthetics on
this are really important to me because
well, just think aesthetics matter.
We're visual creatures and if I'm going
to make something better look good and
this is as simple as it gets. I can
really see something like this work with
the different categories here on the
left and then a clear interface on the
right. If you're building apps, it's
really helpful to have some mockups in
the process. There's various libraries,
but also a quick Google search does it
often times. Just make sure to add this
snippet here to tell it what you
actually like about this image and what
you want to adopt. Then I'm very
specific and say for 6, let's do a and
if you remember 6 was these three
options down here. So we're going with
the zero backend static web app. This
will be perfect for the MVP just like
chatb said. And then I picked three
features that I actually want in here. I
want the dice roll where I can randomize
the fields from the prompt formula to
fill it in and to spark some
inspiration. Also, the book includes
some tone and style presets that I
really enjoy. So, an ability to choose
that right within the website is ideal.
And for people who want to use it in
their automations or agents, markdown
export is a must. Okay, quite simple.
So, basically, I made some choices and
gave it some concrete visual
instructions. A picture says more than a
thousand words, and I use that to my
advantage all the time. Okay, so
underneath it's quite simple. I just
gave it a part of a manuscript to show
it some example prompts. Again, this is
a beginner book that has really been
refined to produce behavioral change in
people. And if you're watching this
video, you're most likely at the deep
end of the AI pool, so to say. So, don't
worry about these prompts. This book is
most likely targeted at your parents or
grandparents. If you're interested, by
the way, I'll put a link to the
pre-order in the description. But that's
not the point. We're building this
application in here. And as soon as I
hit enter, GT5 Pro fought for 9 and 1/2
minutes, and it came back with something
that I was actually really happy with.
No further edits here. This is really
everything I need. It starts with a gold
building block, gives it the text stack,
it describes the layouts that I gave it
via image in detail, maps out the logic,
and then I can import all of the prompts
and more via JSON file. It also has that
functionality. So, I'm just going to
copy paste all of this. And now we're
really ready to build because I have a
very detailed prompt to start here. Now,
I can just copy paste the prompt and hit
enter. And if you have experience with
these apps, you will immediately see
that this is a mix of many things that
you might be familiar with. It looks
like a terminal and has some
similarities with VS Code, but really
it's a hybrid that is optimized for a
human plus AI workflow. You will see it
ask permission on various tasks like
these bash commands just like a terminal
would. And it does everything you would
expect from aentic coding tool. And as I
mentioned, it has a lot of similarities
with other agentic tools like these task
lists. And one tip is that if you log in
with GitHub right away, it has access
and it will work in a brand new repo,
meaning that every time you make
updates, you will have built-in
versioning. So even if you break
something, you can just go back in time.
And it's not just the interface that is
different here. Warp performs
exceptionally on various coding
benchmarks. Of course, the real world
performance is what matters most, but
some of these benchmarks score higher
than claw code, which is definitely not
a bad thing. So at this point, I want to
point out that this tool really shines
if you do know how to work with code
because it shows everything to you over
here. And you could also directly open
the file to make changes right in here.
And there it is. It finished the task
and it's writing the entire readme. And
that's it. It created all of this
autonomously as you would expect. Now
I'll just ask it to open it in my
browser and it will start the
development server and do all of this
for me just like I could do in a command
line interface. But you might be
noticing some of the differences that
this requires zero to no setup. I didn't
have to install GitHub. I didn't have to
set up the repo. I didn't have to
connect API keys. I didn't need an
external application to look at what
it's doing. It's all just in one. Now I
am manually approving the edits, but you
could just hit this and auto approve
everything it's doing. And even some of
these features are things that you just
won't find in something like flaw code
right now. And it's important to note
that I'm not saying that it's clearly
better. It will really depend on what
you're doing. It's just different. And
my hope is that for an actual project
like this, you will get a feeling for
what is different about it and then you
can try it and make an informed decision
for yourself. Okay, let's review the
first version of the application. And
here it is, the first version of our
prompt companion. Okay, so we have the
chapters on the left just like we
wanted. Spacing looks good. I just say
the color theme is a bit bland. I mean,
especially if nothing is selected. So,
if I dice roll, yeah, I get the prompt
preview here. Okay, so this is due for
some changes. I want to hide these
dynamic fields. I want to hide examples
and the return as should look
differently. And then I also want to
change the styling. So, let's see how we
would go about that in here. At this
point in time, I would just want to
commit this to GitHub. So, I have this
version on there. And I'll just auto
approve all these edits. And meanwhile,
I can show you around because if you
open a side pane, you'd have various
resources to make your life easier with
starter prompts, workflows, and you
could also add global or project-based
rules that MCP servers here. If you've
used some of the command line
interfaces, you will know that these
things are possible. They're just not
intuitive. And all of these starter
prompts you kind of have to keep in your
head in an extra file. This really
combines everything into one visual
interface that is made for humans. And
that sort of just makes sense when
you're working with it as a human. Okay,
so this is in Git right now. Now, let's
make the change we talked about. No need
to show the dynamic fields and example
fields. And at this point, I can switch
up my model. So, to edit existing code,
I really like to use some of the more
advanced models. Although, this is a
really simple task. Usually, when you're
laying out a brand new project, even
some of the more economic models like
Sonnet do that super well, but as soon
as you start doing edits, that's when I
personally like to switch up to some of
the higher tier models. Okay, let me
open this project explorer to really see
the changes that are happening in here.
So, here it went into the app.js JS
inside of my source folder as I can see
here and it removed the buttons that I
asked for. Now, this is probably my
favorite thing in here because you can
toggle this open. You can see the exact
changes that it made. It's not just
going to disappear in this endless feed
that a CLI interface often is, but you
can really go in and see, okay, this is
what it removed. This is what it added
instead. And then it also removed some
of the unused state variables that it
set up for this. Now, if I refresh the
page, if something doesn't work as
expected, I can just tell it restart the
dev server. Okay. And there it is. It
removed the two fields. This works well.
So, right now, the main thing is the
design for me. This doesn't really work.
And actually, as I was on a Warp
website, I kind of like what I have
going on here with their website. So,
how about I take inspiration from here
just by taking a screenshot and then
back in Warp. I'll paste that. No
problem at all. Then you can do
something simple like adjust the styling
to align with the attached screenshot.
Let's see how this goes. Okay, let's
have a look. Yes, this is more like it.
Excellent. Excellent. Excellent. A
prompt formula up here. You can dice
roll to get various examples. Okay, just
this thing should work differently. And
this time we'll take a bit of a
different approach. So I can just work
directly with the code. So I can just
look for this functionality that I want
to change. Output format buttons and I
could for example change MD to markdown
save and I don't even have to reload and
you immediately see the change in here.
And if I want to review those changes, I
have this view changes button where I
can see exactly what just happened and
it leads me to the code making my life
as easy as possible. just keeping me in
the loop with everything that's going on
rather than AI just running wild all
over the place. Oh, and another thing is
that I could open multiple windows here.
So, if I want to make this change in
here and I want to start a brand new tab
with the same app here. So, this one I
might want to make the prompt format
more prominent and here I'm changing the
first button. You can work in parallel
and because it tracks the changes so
well, I can make sure that they don't
overlap. Okay, I did both of them at the
same time. And here's the new version. I
love how the formula that's the key here
is highlighted. This button works well.
My final note here is moving this dice
roll button. Oh, and here I actually
caught it doing something I don't want.
I don't want to review the preview card,
just the title. So, I can review the
full changes here. We'll refine this by
saying only review the preview title,
not the entire card. Now, I can tell you
that this is something that inside of a
CLI code editor, you would kind of just
auto approve and then you would be
reverting to a previous version after it
does it all. And that's a real advantage
of this. More control, more overview
because the interface is built for that.
Okay. And here we see the change. Yeah,
this is more like it with the formula.
We can dice roll to get different
examples. And I think that completes the
build here. Now, I might want privacy
policies, more prompts, and maybe some
social media links, but this design and
the functionality aligns with what I
wanted here. I'll just commit this
version to GitHub. And that's it for
now. So, hopefully this workflow
introduced you to this new approach to a
coding interface because I think these
apps are due for an evolution. If you
like what you saw and you appreciate
this mix of us powerful CLI and the
editable code and the deep GitHub
integration, the simple interface, then
go check out Warp today. It's available
for Mac, Windows, and Linux. And they
actually prepared a deal that is almost
too good to be true because for a
limited time, you can get their pro plan
for just $1 in your first month. All you
have to do is go to the link in the
description and use the code eigore to
redeem that offer. And with that being
said, my name is Igor and I'll see you
very